<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Light Ecosystem for Microservices</title>
    <link>https://networknt.github.io/tool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Light Ecosystem for Microservices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 18:06:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://networknt.github.io/tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/tool/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 18:06:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/tool/hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo can be used for document sites for each repository and it can be used to for document site for the entire github organization.
 For repository document, please read here
 For organization document, please read here
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo for networknt.github.io</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/tool/hugo-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 18:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/tool/hugo-org/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As we have known that you can use gh-pages branch to create document site for each repo, there is also a way that you can create a site from your organization and deploy your site to github.com.
The following will describe the process with an example site networknt.github.io
Installation For hugo installation, please read this document
Instructions The detail steps are documented at hugo I am just trying to apply the step to https://networknt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 14:57:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/tool/</guid>
      <description>There are so many tools that help us to build APIs/services regardless they are monolithic applications or microservices and here is a small list.
 Hugo is used to create the document site for networknt.github.io and all our document sites for each repository.
 Memory Monitoring on MacOS while doing performance test
 WRK is used as client for performance test.
 Minikube is a single node Kubernetes cluster for developers to work on laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>