<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples on Light Ecosystem for Microservices</title>
    <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examples on Light Ecosystem for Microservices</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 21:12:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://networknt.github.io/example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 21:12:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/</guid>
      <description>The following examples can be found in light-example-4j repository.
 Database - How to access database
 Microservices - How to build microservices
 Performance - Perforamnce comprison with other frameworks
 Routing - Demo how routing works
 Swagger Specifications - All swagger/OpenAPI specifications
 Web Server - How to integrate API server and Web server together
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Server</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/webserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 08:25:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/webserver/</guid>
      <description>Most documents and articles regarding to Light-4j are about RESTful or GraphQL or Hybrid services; however, there are a lot user cases that combine the API and static site rendering together, especially, single page applications built on top of React or Angular.
Handler Provider As we know, the light-4j needs a plugin to inject application logic and for API project that is based on OpenAPI specification, this is generated by the light-codegen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>routing</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 21:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/routing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is an example to show you how to use undertow routing handler. It opens the door to customize it and put your own handlers in front of common handlers provided.
Location of repo The source code repo can be found at https://github.com/networknt/light-example-4j/tree/master/routing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:55:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/performance/</guid>
      <description>light-4j and all the related light-*-4j frameworks are some of the fastest frameworks to build microservices on the market in different styles. There are several examples that show developers how to implement high performance microservices.
One example can be found at our own microservices benchmark repo which is just test the raw throughput and latency of the framework.
You can find the source code at https://github.com/networknt/microservices-framework-benchmark/tree/master/light-java/a
We also submitted full suite of test cases to Tech Empower to compare with other web frameworks and the source code can be found at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>microservices</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:48:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/microservices/</guid>
      <description>Introduction There are several example applications that have multiple microserivces and they can be found in https://github.com/networknt/light-example-4j/tree/master/rest
These examples will show you:
 How to build microservices How to do API to API call with light-4j client component How to protect API with JWT token with scopes How to performance test APIs with wrk How to centralize logs with ELK How to collect metrics for each services How to deployed with Kubernetes  The tutorials can be found at https://networknt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database</title>
      <link>https://networknt.github.io/example/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:22:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networknt.github.io/example/database/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This example can be found at https://github.com/networknt/light-example-4j/tree/master/database
There are three parts in this projects:
 An API implemented on top of light-4j framework. Mysql database as part of the docker compose with init script. Postgres database as part of the docker compose with init script.  The project shows:
 How to use HikariCP for JDBC connection pool. How to initialize database connection pool and plug it into light-4j startup hooks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>